Olamilekan Wahab

[Machine Learning Engineer]

+2349036671876 | olamyy53@gmail.com | 60, Olorunlogbon St, Anthony, Lagos, Nigeria

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Machine learning engineer with a demonstrated ability to deliver valuable results for machine learning products using insights from various fields and standard software engineering methods. I have been relied on as a key advisor in driving both local and global, million-naira growth; gains in customer loyalty and record setting profit improvements.

My driving goal is to use, support and build well tested machine learning powered products for various business problems. I invest a significant amount of time in understanding and improving existing development tools in the Python ecosystem, especially tools in the data science and machine learning field. I contribute (directly and indirectly) to scikit-learn, matplotlib, pandas and pandas-profiler.

I've researched and built Machine Learning as well as Statistical models to tackle problems such as Recommendations, Sentiment Analysis, Computer VIsion; also, my Software Engineering background ensures I can productionalize these models.

TECHNOLOGIES

ML Libraries	TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch, Scikit-Learn, XGBoost, Apache Spark, Lime, eli5
Data Tools/Libraries	Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scipy, Numpy, Kafka, Apache Storm, PySpark
ML Specialty	Recommender Systems, Natural Language Processing, Click Prediction, Conversion Prediction, LookAlike modelling, Bid Pricing, RTB
ML Cloud Platforms	AWS Machine Learning, AWS Sagemaker, AWS Rekognition, GCP Machine Learning, Azure ML
Languages	Python, JavaScript, Ruby,
Back End (Python)	Django, Flask, Tornado, Fabric, Chalice, WebPy
Back End(PHP)	Codelgniter, Laravel
Back End [Web](JS)	Node, Express, React, React Native

Data Stores	MySQL, Redis, Elasticsearch, Mongo, AWS RedShift, S3, Sqlite
ORMS	PonyORM, SQLAlchemy, Django ORM, Peewee
Web Servers	Apache HTTP Server, Nginx
Hosting Technologies	AWS, Heroku, GCP, PythonAnywhere
Operating Systems	Ubuntu, Mac OS, Windows 10
Miscellaneous	Markovify, RabbitMQ, wxPython, Turtle, Pyramid, ELK Stack

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Machine Learning | Terragon Group | Lagos, Nigeria

2015-Present

Terragon uses Machine Learning to power various adtech networks and processes nationwide

- Built and maintained Machine Learning models that led to an improvement, from 1% to 5% in the click through rate (CTR) for campaigns and from 0.3% to 3% in conversion rate (CVR)
- Initiated and implemented training strategies for new talents which enhanced employee on boarding by 30%.
- Built a real time computer vision platform for crowd monitoring that informs clients about age, gender and count of everyone at an event.
- Built an admin platform where all machine learning product performance is tracked.
- Implemented designs for various products while considering the need for easy experimentation and load testing.
- Modified existing softwares to correct errors, upgrade interfaces and generally improve performance.
- Built a platform to rapidly prototype new capabilities to confirm feasibility.
- Researched, designed and implemented a scalable application for information identification, extraction, analysis, retrieval and indexing.
- Worked effectively with design teams to ensure software solutions elevated client side experience.
- Worked closely with other team members to plan, design and develop robust solutions in a timely manner.
- Responsible for data integrity and ease of access.
- <u>Technologies:</u> Python, Scikit-learn, Keras, Codelgniter, Flask, WebPy, Chalice, RabbitMQ, SMOTE, matplotlib, seaborn, AWS, AWS Sagemaker, AWS Machine Learning

Contract Machine Learning Engineer | Sikilabs | Lagos, Nigeria
Sikilabs uses the latest python technologies to build various products for it's clients

2018-Present

- Worked directly with product and other team members to build a machine learning powered platform for large scale image/music classification.
- Researched and updated all required materials needed for projects to be successful.
- Implemented testing features on all platforms
- Built https://myradart.com and tontine.com
- <u>Technologies:</u> Python, Scikit-learn, matplotlib, seaborn, Digital Ocean, React

MS Research Internship Microsoft | Remote and On-Site(Cambridge) Had an extensive 3 month research internship courtesy of Microsoft

- Learnt how to do standard research in the ML space which included how to
 - o Do literature review and how to summarise findings

- Formulate research questions and designing studies
- Preparing research reports.
- o Presenting result of research projects to a faculty of experienced researchers
- Worked extensively with a team to achieve various team set goals.

Contract Machine Learning Engineer | Unit9 | Lagos, Nigeria

2017-2018

Unit9 uses various technologies to build high end digital platforms for it's clients.

- Worked directly with product and other team members to build a machine learning powered platform for large scale image/music classification.
- Designed and developed schema based data models
- Developed a scalable machine learning powered finance application for the firm
- Provided insights on data standardisation and usage to ensure data integrity
- Transformed project data requirements into project data models
- Technologies: Python, tensorflow, matplotlib, seaborn, GCP, React, Facebook Messenger

Contract Software Instructor | Code Institute | Lagos, Nigeria

2016 - 2017

- Taught students of various backgrounds and interest various web technologies
- Taught students Python and Django for backend development
- Implementing designs, including experimentation and multiple iterations
- Taught students JQuery, JavaScript, D3js and Angular for frontend development
- Provided group teaching in a classroom setting, as well as individual student support.
- Advised students on crucial software decisions.
- Identified students' interests, weaknesses and strengths
- Technologies: Python, Django, Heroku, C9

Contract Software Engineer | Healthier | Lagos, Nigeria

2016 - 2016

- Developed the Healthier medical platform for purchasing, handling and dispatching medical data and tools
- <u>Technologies:</u> Python, Django, Heroku, BlueHost

Contract Software Engineer | Lucy | Lagos, Nigeria Lucy provides branded art and craft products.

2015-2016

- Provided key suggestions in the design, development, testing and support of the Lucy platforms
- Built registry.lucy.ng and instadriver.com.ng
- Design, implemented and monitored web pages and sites for continuous improvement in a fast paced environment.
- Utilised programming capabilities in PHP, SQL and JavaScript.
- <u>Technologies:</u> PHP, Codelgniter, Heroku, JS, CSS, JQuery

TALKS/PRESENTATION

2018

- PyConNigeria: Natural Language Processing: The Need for a Yoruba Corpus
- Al Saturday Lagos: Building and debugging classifiers.
- Data Science Nigeria: Machine Learning in AdTech

2017

- AlterConf : Succeeding as a student developer
- Data Science Lautech : Machine Learning in Academia
- DangoGirls OAU and LAUTECH
- Leverage Ife: Machine Learning Panel

2016

Django Girls Lagos

VOLUNTEERING

PyCON Nigeria 2017-2018

- Worked with the organising team to set up the conference
- Helped review talks
- Assisted in setting up the conference
- Helped in getting the speakers set up.
- Generally provided any form of other help I could

Diango Girls 2015-2016-2017

- introduced over 30 girls from OAU, FUTA, LAGOS and OGBOMOSHO to python web technologies
- Followed up with the girls to provide technical support and answer any questions they might have

Intel Student Community Member 2014

- Worked with the community to introduce students to Python, Scratch and Intel based technologies like the XDK
- Met weekly to resolve technical issues with the introduced technologies and to look at more.

Python Club 2014

- Led the team to introduce students to Python and it's ecosystem
- Worked with the team to get more students to use and understand web technologies in Python(majorly flask and django).
- Spread the club's activities to neighbouring schools.

Other Communities: IEEE OAU, ICSE OAU

EDUCATION

- Udacity Nanodegree
- MIT Micromaster ¹
- Coursera Probability and Data
- Stats 202
- Andrew NG Coursera

BSc Electronics Electrical Engineering | Obafemi Awolowo University | Ile-Ife, Nigeria² 2014 – 2017

NOUN | Mathematics | Lagos, Nigeria 2018

University of Leeds-Becket Diploma

PROFILES

Blog <u>Olamilekan's Blog</u>

GITHUB Olamyy (Olamilekan Wahab) · GitHub

LINKEDIN <u>linkedin.com/in/olamilekan-mufrad-wahab-137679120/</u>